Here comes another psychic.
（悪霊）
また霊媒師が来ましたよ
What should we do with them, Dimple-san?
（悪霊）
エクボさ～ん どうしましょうか？
（エクボ）
どうせ また偽者だろ？　追っ払え
Probably just another fake.
Get 'em to scram.
Oh, shit...
（悪霊たち）
ヤベえ！　ヤツは本物だ！
He's...
the real deal!
Mob Psycho
Inside
~Evil Spirit~
This job we just got is huge!
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
今回の依頼はデカいぞ
Cup Curry
I still don't know the details,
内容は まだ分からんが
依頼主は有名な資産家で―
but the client is a famously wealthy fellow.
We're talking super rich.
“超”の付く金持ちだ
タクシー代も出る
He'll even pay for our taxi.
（モブ）
でも 電車で行くんですね
And yet we're taking a train?
So is this rich person the president
of a company or something?
金持ちって 社長か何かですか？
He is.
社長だ
これ 個人の持ち家なのか？
How can one person own a house like this?
Get a load of all these shady-looking people.
見るからに
うさんくさい雰囲気をまとってるな
They're probably from the same field.
多分 同業者だ
Hey, you two.
（森羅万象丸(しんらばんしょうまる)）
よう！　お前ら
あっ 森羅万象丸さん
Shinra Banshomaru-san.
What the heck are you doing here?
なんでお前が ここにいるんだ？
Right back at you.
（森羅）
そりゃ こっちのセリフだ
Shinra-kun.
（浄堂麒麟(じょうどうきりん)）
森羅君
Jodo-sama!
（森羅）
浄堂様！
Jodo Kirin
Rising Sun Spiritual Union President
Who is that man?
（浄堂）
誰だね その男は？
He helped me with getting
rid of an evil spirit once.
（森羅）
以前 悪霊相手に
共闘したことがある―
This is Reigen Arataka, a freelance psychic.
霊幻新隆という
フリーの霊能力者です
ほ～う 君が例の？
Ah, so this is the man...
The one who's been lying about
getting rid of the Dragger?
おひきさんを退治したと
デマを吹聴しているという
Pleased to meet ya.
よろしく～
（霊能力者たち）
あれが浄堂？　目を合わすな！
不気味なじじいだ
So that's Jodo?
Avoid eye contact!
What a creepy geezer!
（魔津尾(まつお)）
なっ ヤツらは！
It's them!
Having a rough time trying
to get into the psychic biz
Former Upper Echelon Member of
Claw's Seventh Division
Matsuo
Are they going to get in my way again?
But I'm running a legit business now!
まっとうに生きようと
始めた私の商売まで
邪魔する気？
Here he comes.
（霊能力者１）来たぞ
（霊能力者２）依頼人だ
It's the client.
I thank all of you professionals
for gathering here today.
（浅桐正志(あさぎりまさし)）
よく集まってくださいました
先生方
Asagiri Holdings (Ltd.) CEO
Asagiri Masashi
I have no doubts that you
are all true psychics.
私は 皆さんが本物の
霊能力者であることに
疑いを持っておりません
But whether any of you can save my daughter
is a different matter entirely.
しかし この中に娘を救える方が
いらっしゃるかどうか
I ask that you keep what
you're about to see a secret.
ここから先は どうぞ内密に
This is my daughter, Asagiri Minori.
She's fourteen years old.
私の娘 浅桐みのり 14歳です
She is behind a one-way mirror,
so she cannot see us.
マジックミラーなので
向こうからは見えません
She's the same age as Mob.
モブと同い年か
He has her locked up?
Isn't that going too far?
（霊能力者）
ちょっと
やりすぎなんじゃねえか？
At first, I didn't believe in spirits, either.
最初は 私も
信じていなかったんですよ 霊など
But no matter how many counselors or
mental health professionals we saw,
しかし いくら心理カウンセラーや
精神治療の権威に―
当たってみたところで
まるで効果がない
there was no improvement.
She's been possessed by an evil spirit.
彼女の中には
悪霊が入ってしまったのです
I'd like for you all to rid her of it.
先生方には
それを退治していただきたい
What do you think?
どう思う？
Right now, I'm not sensing anything.
今のところ
これっぽっちも感じませんね
It's probably some mental disorder
stemming from adolescence.
思春期の精神的疾患が
妥当なところだな
I do sense a faint sinister
presence though...
しかし かすかに
醜悪な気配がするな
And extremely nearby.
それも すぐ近くで
No price is too high!
金に糸目は つけません！
I will have a special reward
for whoever saves my daughter!
救ってくれた者には
特別な報酬を用意する！
よ～し！
Very well.
Guess we'll take care of this
in a jiffy once again.
じゃあ 今回も俺たちが
スパ～ッと解決してやるか
What do you say, Mob?
I'll be sure to give you a bonus.
なあ モブ？
お前にもボーナスやるよ
A bonus... That's a first.
ボーナス！　初めてだ
You've been underpaid this whole time.
つうか 今までが少なすぎんだろ！
Hold it! You're not going
to steal the march on us!
待てい！　抜け駆けは許さんぞ！
Namu
Who said you could decide?!
（霊能力者たち）
勝手に決めるな！　ズルいぞ！
俺にやらせろ！
No fair!
Let me do it!
Everyone, please, calm down.
皆さん そう慌てずに！
How about we do
rock-paper-scissors to decide?
ジャンケンで決めるというのは
どうでしょう？
Huh? Rock-paper-scissors?
（霊能力者たち）
は？　ジャンケン？
I guess that's fair.
（霊能力者たち）
それなら公平だな
いいだろう　だな！
Sure.
Yeah.
All right, I'm gonna throw paper.
よし！　俺はパーを出すぞ
Huh?
（霊能力者たち）
は？　何だ その宣言は？
Why are you telling us that?
Actually, I think I'll go with scissors.
やっぱり チョキを出す
Uh, no, really...
いや だからさ…
Leave him be. That's just how he is.
ほっとけ　ああいうヤツなんだ
So is he going to throw paper or scissors?
（魔津尾）
パーなの？　チョキなの？
First comes rock!
（霊能力者たち）
最初はグー ジャンケンぽん！
Rock, paper,
scissors!
Reigen emerged victorious.
（ナレーション）
霊幻は優勝した
Wow, how did you do that?
（モブ）
すごい　どうやったんですか？
Psychological Warfare
Observation
Line of Sight
Their Hand Angles
Scan their arms
Etc.
I will never lose to anyone
in rock-paper-scissors.
ジャンケンなら
誰にも負けねえ自信がある
フフン じゃあ おっ先～！
See ya, losers.
I never should've said I knew him.
（森羅）
知り合いなんて言うんじゃなかった
Please save my daughter.
娘をどうかお願いします！
I've got it.
I can't provide the professional help she needs.
Not on our first meeting, at that.
（霊幻）
精神的な疾患を
初対面の素人がケアするのは厳しい
All I can do here is
approach this as a psychic.
ここで俺ができることは
あくまで霊能者としてだけ
Hello there.
こんにちは
Yes, like I always do.
（霊幻）
そう いつもどおりだ
Do you know why you're locked in here?
なんで閉じ込められてるのか
分かる？
I don't...
（浅桐みのり）
あたし 分からないの
There's something wrong with Papa lately.
パパ 最近 おかしいのよ
With your father?
（霊幻）
お父さんが？
Lately, he's locked me up in here,
strapped me down onto this bed,
（みのり）
少し前から私を閉じ込めたり
ベッドに縛りつけたり
started glaring at me,
and even hit me sometimes.
怖い顔でにらんだり
たたいたりもするのよ
That's not—I mean,
I didn't hit her hard...
（浅桐）
そんな！
いや 強くたたいたりなんかは…
はっ！
He's even brought around a bunch of adults
（みのり）
いろんな大人たちを
連れてきては―
and had them touch me all over
with their filthy, filthy hands.
あたしの体を
ベタベタ触らせたりもしたのよ
Th-That's preposterous!
そ… そんなことあるわけが…
You can't believe a word Dad says.
（みのり）
お父さんを信じちゃダメよ
He's been acting so darn crazy lately,
like he's possessed.
最近 まるで何かに
取りつかれたみたいに おかしいの
どんなふうに？
How so?
He started saying that I've been cursed,
（みのり）
私が呪われてるとか
or that my body's been taken over by a demon.
悪魔に乗っ取られてるとか
言いだしたのよ
I mean, I guess I was acting
a little rebellious,
そりゃ ちょっと反抗期も
あったかもしれないけど
but this is going way too far.
ここまでするなんて異常よ
I-I assure you that I'm sane!
わ… 私は正常だ！　バカげてる！
This is ridiculous!
There's a demon that's making
my daughter say these lies!
悪魔が娘にウソを
言わせているんだ！
Am I going to be trapped in here forever?
私 ずっとこのまま
出られないのかな？
Say, Mr. Psychic...
ねえ 霊能者さん
could ya undo these for me?
これ 外してくれない？
They hurt so bad!
痛くてしょうがないの
お父さんに聞いてみるよ
I'll ask your dad.
How'd it go?
どうだった？
This is an open-and-shut case.
（浄堂）
調べるまでもない
She is perfectly normal.
あの子は正常じゃよ
You think so too, Jodo-sama?
（浄堂の取り巻き）
浄堂様も そう思いますか？
What? What do you mean?
（浅桐）
なんだと！　どういうことだ？
We're saying that there's zero
possibility that she's possessed.
（取り巻き）
彼女に悪霊がついた可能性は
ゼロだということだ
No, that can't be true!
（浅桐）
いや そんなはずはないんだ！
It's my turn next.
But I'm rather certain Jodo-sama is correct.
（宇藤(うどう)）
次は私の番だ
浄堂様の言うとおりだと思うが…
But wait—
（浅桐）
いや しかし…
Are you sure you're not the problem here?
（霊能力者）
問題があるのは あなたでは？
You don't like the change in your
relationship and refuse to accept it.
家族の変化に対応できず
認めようとしない
Instead, you're blaming spirits and demons.
あげく霊や悪魔のせいだと言い張る
N-No...
そ… そんな！
Is that really how you guys
talk to a client?
お前ら 依頼人に何 言ってんだ！
That's a nasty one.
ありゃ タチが悪いぞ
間違いなく黒だ
Definitely something wrong there.
It didn't feel like I was
talking to a child.
子供と会話してる気がしなかった
おおっ！　私を信じてくれるのか！
So you believe me?
You just want the reward money
all to yourself, don't you?
とか言って 報酬を
独り占めしたいだけなんじゃ？
あの子にダマされたヤツは
帰ったほうがいい
Everyone who actually fell for
what she said should leave now.
She's just going to make a fool of you.
まんまと取り込まれるぜ
The way she talked was too inconsistent.
１人称がコロコロ変わったり
And she switched from "Papa" to "Dad."
“パパ”と言ったり
“お父さん”と言ったり
Also, I never introduced myself,
それと 俺は
ただ話をしただけなのに
but she called me a psychic.
彼女は俺を“霊能者”と呼んだ
Meaning she heard our conversation out h—
つまり こっちの会話が筒抜け…
（霊能力者たち）
うわ～！　何だ 何だ？
Udo! Are you all right?!
（取り巻き）
宇藤！　大丈夫か？
Get a hold of yourself!
Sh-She's a monster...
ば… 化け物だ
Master!
師匠！
I'm fine.
俺は大丈夫だ
More importantly, she sure showed
her true colors pretty fast.
それより 化けの皮が剥がれるのが
早かったな
I guess there's no point in
continuing this charade.
見破られたのなら もういい
Go ahead and try to force me
out of this girl!
（悪霊の声で）
私をこの娘から追い出してみろ！
誰か 娘を助けてやってくれ！
I beg of you!
Somebody please save my daughter!
とにかく あの悪魔を
追い出してくれれば
I will pay you anything if you can
rid my daughter of that demon!
報酬は惜しまん！
Two hundred million!
Five hundred million!
２億でも ５億でも！
Yawn
Lick Lick Lick
フウ フウ～
Namu
ふん！
Here I go! I'm gonna drink it!
いいか 飲むぞ！
I'm getting bored of this.
（悪霊）
飽きてきたな
Your turn might be coming up soon.
このままだと出番が回ってくるぞ
ウオームアップしとけ
Winner
49th out of 68
Make sure you warm up a bit.
You're making it sound like a workout.
筋トレみたいな言い方ですね
There are no warmups for this.
ないですよ そんなの
Suikoden
What's wrong, Dimple?
You're shaking like crazy.
どうした エクボ？
えらくおびえてんな
Are you a chihuahua?
（モブ）
チワワ？
（エクボ）
まだ間に合う
There's still time... Drop this job!
この案件から手を引け！
Huh?
I'm sure you've at least heard of
his name before... Mogami Keiji.
お前らも 名前くらいは
知ってるだろう？
最上啓示(もがみけいじ)
知らない
Nope.
（霊幻）
最上…
Mogami...
He's one of the people I referenced
when I first started in this biz.
この商売を始めるときに
参考にした１人だ
He's been dead for ages, though.
とっくに死んでたけど…
40年前の話だ
We're talking about forty years ago!
40 Years Ago
Mogami Keiji
（ナレーション）
最上啓示
Mogami Keiji.
Mogami Keiji performs a seance
He was known as a good psychic who used
seances and channeling to save people,
霊視 口寄せなどの能力を生かし
人々を救う善良な霊能力者として
Mogami Keiji
The voices of the dead
and the media loved him.
各種メディアから
引っ張りだこだった
But what the masses were seeing
was Mogami Keiji the entertainer.
だが 国民が見ていたのは
あくまでタレントの最上啓示だ
Psychic
Mogami Keiji
And then one day,
ヤツは あるときを境に
パッタリと表舞台から姿を消した
he completely vanished
from the public eye.
Mogami had another side to him.
最上には裏の顔があった
He was an assassin
who used his powers to kill.
独自の呪術による暗殺だ
Mogami was desperate for money.
最上は金を求めていた
His mother was gravely ill,
母親が重い病気になり
and the treatment and equipment
she needed cost a lot of money.
治療費と十分な設備が
必要だったんだ
Be it the living or the dead, seeing their
final moments had become routine for him.
生者と死者
それぞれの最期に関わる日常が
当たり前になることで
And it broke him.
ヤツは壊れていった
And that's around the time
そんな頃だ
ヤツが俺様の除霊に現れたのは
he showed up to exorcise me.
How dare you do that to my followers?!
（エクボ）
よくも俺様の子分どもを！
I'm going full power for this!
フル霊力でいくぜ！
ぐお～！
Overrun! Wraither Beam!
拡散霊(レー)ザービーム！
あっ！　参った！
I give up!
Wait, I said I give up!
I won't do anything bad ever again!
参ったって！
もう何も悪さしねえからよ！
What are you talking about?
（最上啓示）
何 言ってる？
You seem to have the wrong idea.
お前は勘違いしている
I've come to absorb you.
私は お前を取り込みに来たんだ
A-Absorb me?
（エクボ）
と… 取り込むって？
うっ こいつ
This bastard...
He's human, but he's absorbing
my spiritual molecules!
人間なのに霊素を
体内に吸収してる！
Are you trying to eat me?
俺様を食う気か？
You'll just end up with an upset stomach!
体に毒なだけだぞ！
I am going to willfully
shuffle off this mortal coil soon
（最上）
私は もうじき自ら命を絶ち
強力な怨霊になる
and become a powerful vengeful spirit.
Shit! This bastard's completely lost it!
（エクボ）
ヤベえ トんでる
Wh-Why would you do that?
ど… どうして そんなことを？
Revenge.
復讐(ふくしゅう)だ
I'm going to show all those bastards who
think nothing bad will ever happen to them.
自分だけは安全だと思っている
連中に分からせてやる
Show them what true hatred is like.
恨みとは どういうものかを
And what happens when they
manipulate and use someone.
それは
他人を利用することのリスクだ
You're going to empower me
to achieve that goal.
お前は その糧になれ
（最上）
うっ…
一度に悪霊を食らい過ぎたようだ
It appears I absorbed too many
vengeful spirits at once.
It got away?
逃げたか
Hang on a sec.
（霊幻）
ちょっと待った
What's that got to do with anything?
その話 何の関係がある？
That's Mogami himself!
（エクボ）
あれは本人だよ
The star psychic of the 20th century,
Mogami Keiji!
世紀の霊能力者 最上啓示
Or what's become of him.
その成れの果てだ
（霊能力者）
ううっ！　うぐっ…
たひゅけて　ほべんにゃはい
Please... spare... me...
（最上）
さよなら
Goodbye.
フウ…
As I figured, this is all you're worth.
（最上）
やはり こんな程度か
質が低い
You're all so weak,
I have no reason to let you live!
見逃す価値がないほどに悲しいぞ
How sad.
Apparently, it's finally my time to shine.
（浄堂）
ようやく順番が回ってきたようじゃ
It's a shame that I'm so bad
at rock-paper-scissors.
まったく
ジャンケンが弱くて 参った
Are you supposed to be a famous psychic?
I don't recognize you.
（最上）
大物の霊能者なのか？　知らんな
Please... God...
お願いだ 神様！
Begone... foul spirit!
（浄堂）
往生せい！
Jodo-sama's getting serious!
浄堂様の本気だ！
This will be enlightening!
勉強になる
He's not even bothering with chants
or throwing salt around, huh?
お経を唱えたり
塩 まいたりしないんだな
Que?
くえっ
Hey, something's wrong.
（霊能力者たち）
様子が変だぞ！
もしかして乗っ取られてないか？
Did he get possessed?
That's it?
（最上）
この程度で…
Hey, explain something to me.
おい 教えてくれよ
What makes this guy such a big shot?
こいつのどこが大物なんだ？
Here he comes.
（モブ）うわっ 来る！
（エクボ）逃げろ 茂夫(しげお)！
Run, Shigeo!
Anti-Possession Jumping Knee Strike!
（霊幻）
対被憑依(ひょうい)者飛び膝蹴り！
A jumping knee strike to knock
a possessed person unconscious.
（ナレーション）
憑依された者に飛び膝蹴りをかまし
Anti-Possession Jumping Knee Strike
意識を強制的に飛ばす
霊幻の必殺技である
This is one of Reigen's special attacks.
Jodo-sama!
（取り巻きたち）
浄堂様！
Sorry!
すまん！
Hey, evil spirit!
やい 悪霊！
If my intuition's correct,
you're actually Mogami Kei—
俺の勘だと お前の正体は
最上啓…
うぐっ！
You know who I am?
（最上）
私を知っているのか？
Damn, it was true?!
（霊幻）
本当だったのかよ！
Why the hell are you possessing that girl?
何が目的で女の子に
取りついてんだ？
Were you into young girls
when you were alive—
生前もロリコンだった… うぐっ
T-Time out...
ちょ… タンマ
（モブ）
止まらない
He's not stopping!
う… ぐう…
Minori.
（浅桐）
みのり！　もう やめなさい
Stop this.
I'll stay by your side.
パパが一緒にいてやるから
Get awa...
離れ… ろ…
（浅桐）
ぐはっ…
He impaled him!
（モブ）
刺した
You can't... be serious...
（霊幻）
ウソだろ？
I didn't come here to see someone die!
人が死ぬなんて聞いてないぞ！
We can't deal with that monster!
（霊能力者たち）
こんなの 相手にしてられるか！
逃げろ～！
Run!
I-It won't open?!
（霊能力者たち）
あ… 開かない！
冗談じゃねえ！　助けてくれ～！
No way!
Let us out!
Where do you think you're going?
（最上）
どこに行こうっていうんだ？
Well, this has gone to shit.
とんでもない
ありさまだな
Mob, you warmed up yet?
モブ
肩は温まってるか？
Yes.
はい
全然 温まってないけど
やるしかないのは分かります
Well, I'm not actually warmed up at all,
but I know I have to deal with this anyway.
Progress
Towards
Mob's
Explosion
Mob Psycho
A demon...
（霊能力者たち）
悪魔だ
逃げたほうが いいんじゃ…
Shouldn't we run away?
I'm pretty confident in my abilities.
私も多少は腕に覚え… がはっ！
（霊能力者たち）
ぐはっ！　うおっ！　うわっ！
Spirit Hold!
（森羅）
霊縛(れいばく)！
Oh?
（最上）
ほ～う　誰かは分からないが
優れた念動力者だな
I don't know who it is, but someone's
got some decent telekinetic powers.
It's true that humans can't move
their joints past a certain point.
確かに体の関節は
可動域以上 動かすことはできない
But what about a doll's joints?
でも 人形の関節はどうだ？
（最上）
フフフ 動けるよ！
Oh, look. I can move.
That girl's body...
（モブ）
あの子の体が！
Get it now?
（最上）
分かったか？
Nothing you do to this body will affect me.
It's not a solution.
この体に負荷をかけても
何の解決にもならん
What are you laughing about?
（モブ）
なにを笑ってるんだ
（最上）
彼か
It's him.
There is a solution.
（モブ）
解決はするよ
I'll make you disappear.
僕が お前を消す！
Now we're talking!
こっからだ！
Such incredible spiritual power...
（魔津尾）
なんて霊力！
What the hell is that?
（霊能力者たち）
何だよ あれ？　見たことねえ！
I've never seen anything like it!
Get out of Minori-san... Now!
みのりさんから出ていけ！
Amazing...
すごい
I thought he was just some kid,
子供かと思ったら なんてパワーだ
but he's insanely powerful!
Forget being possessed!
They're fusing into one now!
（魔津尾）
いや 憑依どころか 融合しかけてる
I messed up...
（モブ）
失敗した
Master, the situation's gotten even worse.
師匠 状況が もっと悪くなりました
You're telling me he's
stronger than you, Mob?
（霊幻）
モブより強いってのか？
（モブ）
はい
Yes.
No way...
ウソ…
That bastard... He's even livelier now
than when he was alive!
野郎 死ぬ前よりも
生き生きしてやがる！
（最上）
ハッハッハッ 終わりか 小僧？
You done, kid?
（霊能力者たち）
ひるむな！　今しかねえ！
Now's our only chance!
（霊能力者たち）
ぐわ～！
That bastard actually did it.
ヤツは なっていたんだ
望みどおり 最強の悪霊に！
He became the most powerful evil spirit...
Well, if you die and can't pass on,
at least we'll have each other.
まあ 死んで成仏できなかったら
改めて よろしくな
Don't even joke about that!
縁起でもねえぞ！
I see.
（モブ）そうか
（２人）え？
I can go inside of Minori-san
and expel the evil spirit from within.
みのりさんの中に入って
内側から悪霊を追い出せば…
Are you stupid?!
アホか！
How's a human like you going
to enter another human?!
生身の人間が
どうやって他人の中に入るんだよ！
With an out of body experience.
（モブ）
幽体離脱だよ
I see...
なるほどな
But during that time, your body
will be completely defenseless.
だが その間
お前の肉体は無防備になるぜ
Not to mention her body will resist you!
それに 幽体になったところで
侵入を拒絶してくるぞ
But I have no other choice.
でも やるしかないんだ
Dimple, could you possess my body
for a while and protect it?
エクボ 少しの間 憑依して
僕の体を守ってくれないかな？
Say what?
No, no! Anything but that, Mob!
いやいや それはやめとけ モブ
こいつ そのまま乗っ取るぞ 多分
If you let him in,
he'll probably never leave.
どういうことか
分かってんだろうな？
You know what you're signing up for, right?
Are you seriously going to trust Dimple?
マジでエクボを信用するのか？
I'm sure it'll be fine.
きっと大丈夫ですよ
まず 意識を失わなきゃ
First, I need to lose consciousness.
Concentrate...
集中して…
Has he changed a little?
（霊幻）
ちょっと変わったか こいつ？
Or wait... Is he trying to change himself?
いや 自分を
変えようとしているのか？
Whoa!
Holy shit! Even I can see it!
（霊幻）
スゲえ 俺にも見える！
うわっ 来やがった
He's coming!
この！
Take that!
Wait a sec!
ちょっと待って！　ええ～！
ぐはっ
うぐ…
It's no use... I can't move.
（霊幻）
ダメだ 動けねえ
If you don't need this body anymore,
why don't I take it off your hands?
（最上）
この肉体 いらんのなら
私が使おうか？
You dumbass.
（エクボ）
バカめ
It belongs to me now!
もう俺様のもんだ！
That's what you get!
ざま～見やがれ！
Whoa there!
おっと！
I'm not gonna let you break
my precious body that easily!
大事な素材を
そう やすやすと壊されて
たまるかよ！
Why's there another spirit?
What a nuisance.
（最上）
なぜ ほかの霊がいる？　目障りだ
消えろ
Begone.
今だ 茂夫！
Now, Shigeo!
So that's your game...
（最上）
そういうことか　正気じゃないな
You must be insane.
Yeah, he's not a normal kid.
そいつは普通のガキじゃねえんだよ
Go...
いけ… お前なら… 勝てる
I know you can... win...
Welcome.
（最上）
ようこそ
自我は残っているのか？
Is your sense of self still intact?
If you'd made one misstep getting in here,
your soul would've been destroyed.
侵入に失敗したら
幽体ごと消滅していたぞ
ここから出ていってください
Please leave this body.
You didn't come here to talk, did you?
（最上）
対話をしに来たんじゃないだろ？
（モブ）
はい
Correct, but you seem so human.
でも あまりに人間っぽいので
We're currently in a mental world.
（最上）
ここは精神世界だからな
It mirrors the way we see ourselves.
姿形も思考が反映される
I'm Mogami Keiji, a former psychic.
私は最上啓示　元霊能者だ
How about we have a little contest?
勝負しようじゃないか
A barrier, eh?
（最上）
バリアか　すばらしい力だ
Very impressive.
Mind showing me a little more?
もう少し見せてくれないか？
He's got his evil spirit face on now.
（モブ）
悪霊の顔になってる
なんてパワーだ
Such power...
がはっ ああ…
You've truly been blessed...
with incredible power...
非常に恵まれた能力を持っているな
That's a ghost... An evil spirit...
（モブ）
あれは霊体だ　悪霊なんだ
By the way, young man...
ところで 少年よ
Do you know where spiritual
power or ESP comes from?
霊能力や超能力が
どこから湧いて出るか知ってるか？
Sorry, but I don't have any more time.
悪いけど 時間がないんだ
とどめを刺すよ
I'm going to finish you now.
Your emotions.
感情だよ　全ては感情が生むものだ
It all comes from your emotions.
The biggest distinguishing feature of humans
is how rich and varied their emotions are.
（最上）
人間が持つ最大の特徴が
その豊富な感情だ
These emotions are the reason they thrive
and also the reason they fight.
感情があるから
繁栄もするし 争いも起きる
Huh? My powers...
（モブ）
あれ？　力が…
You can't use ESP anymore.
（最上）
君は もう超能力を使えない
I was gauging how you
picture your powers earlier.
さっきのは 君のイメージする力を
測ってみたんだ
Quite impressive.
大したものだ
多くの感情が波打っている
All kinds of emotions
are raging inside of you.
But for some reason,
you willingly play the part of a puppet.
しかし 自ら利用される側に
落ち着いている
Please... leave...
ここから 出て…
You still don't get the fact
that you fell into a trap?
（最上）
まだ分からないのか？
ワナに はまったことが
I let you in on purpose.
私は わざと君を受け入れたんだ
Now, here's the million-dollar question.
では ここで問題だ
People whose lives are filled with happiness,
and people who live in eternal suffering...
幸せに暮らしている人間と
苦しみに もがいている人間
Which do you think harbor
strong emotions more easily?
どちらのほうが
強い感情が育つと思う？
The answer is the latter.
正解は後者
Negative feelings are much more powerful.
より強いのは負の感情だ
The more stressed someone is,
the richer the energy they hold within.
ストレスを抱え込んでいる者ほど
内に秘めたエネルギーは濃い
Going by that, there's room for
more drastic change in you.
その点を踏まえれば―
君は今よりもっと強く
変わることができる
All you need is a slight change
in how you see the world.
世界の見方を少し変えるだけでな
Want me to help you out?
協力してやろうか？
うう… 朝か
It's morning...
Kageyama Shigeo.
（最上）
影山茂夫
Here, you're a normal middle schooler.
ここでは普通の中学生だ
I altered your memories a bit,
and made it so you can't use ESP.
君の記憶を少し操作し
超能力も使えなくしてある
A change in perspective can make
the world a whole different place.
視点が違えば 世界は別物だ
With that in mind, I'll be observing
how you act without your powers.
そのうえで
超能力の使えない君を
観察させてもらおう
Huh? What was I doing again?
（モブ）
あれ？　僕 何してたんだっけ？
I was doing something important...
何か大事なことを…
全然 思い出せないや
But I can't remember it at all.
Oh, I should hurry up and get to school.
あっ 早く学校 行かなきゃ
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 II Episode 5:
次回「モブサイコ100 Ⅱ」
第５話“不和　選択”
Discord
~Choices~
"Discord ~Choices~."